# JOZEF LACKO

### Profile:

I am a software engineer with 5 years work experience strongly concentrated on building Web applications using JavaScript and TypeScript.

- Full name Jozef Lacko
- Address Vienna. Austria
- **Born** January 27th, 1989
- **Email** jlacko27@gmail.com
- Phone +436603279298
- Web www.jozeflacko.com

## Skills:

Mainly JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Css and Html. I have experience also with other languages and technologies as Java and C. I believe that I have a good sense for design, details and presentation skills.

## Languages:

- Slovak Native
- English Advanced
- German Advanced
- Russian Intermediate
- Hungarian Beginner

### Other:

I consider myself as a very honest and happy person who believes that motivation can be more valuable than experience. I love to talk about life and I always search for positive people. I use my free time to develop small projects with my friends.

More info:



## **Education:**

September 2013 - May 2015

➤ Master of Engineering in Business Informatics

Technical University of Kosice, Slovakia Faculty of Electrical Engineering and Informatics Overall classification of the qualification: 89.9%

September 2010 - June 2013

➤ Bachelor of Engineering in Business Informatics

Technical University of Kosice, Slovakia

Faculty of Electrical Engineering and Informatics

Overall classification of the qualification: 84.9%

## Work Experience:

January 2019 - Present

➤ Agile Developer at Österreichische Lotterien GmbH, Vienna, Austria
I work at Austrian Lotteries as a React/TypeScript developer in a small team of
7 people. My main role is to design and build web-front-end with the latest
tech-stack. I define concepts and build Apis for layouting, validation, testing and

other. This is my first fully german speaking job.

June 2015 - December 2018

➤ Web Software Engineer at Workflow EDV GmbH, Vienna, Austria

I was the major Frontend developer of the enterprise web application, focusing mostly on time, travel and personnel management. I worked with technologies including JavaScript, Css, Html, Xslt, Xml, Java, Spring, Maven, BPMN Workflows. My main responsibilities were the development of the responsive skin of our progressive web app and significantly improving the user experience. Product contained 350+ Uls which needed a lot of analytical and design skills. In the company I started as a full-time trainee and switched to regular contract after 10 months. The Company won "Technology Excellence Award 2019" for innovative technology and solution quality in the categories of functional scope, usability and intuitive handling.

September 2014 - October 2014

➤ Software Engineer - Internship at University of Tokyo, Japan

With the help of IAESTE exchange program, I was accepted for a 10 weeks internship at University of Tokyo in Japan. Internship was aimed to effectiveness of parallel computation with Fortran programming language. It was my first experience abroad and a great opportunity to experience other cultures, for which I am absolutely thankful.

April 2015 - May 2015, July 2014 - November 2014

➤ Web Software Engineer at Technical University of Kosice, Slovakia

<u>I have been selected from among more than 200 students to work on the university projects.</u> Our client was one of the subsidiaries of the United States Steel Corporation placed in Slovakia. In a team of 7 people, we implemented C# ASP.Net Razor enterprise web applications responsible for managing production of an iron ore. My main responsibility was Frontend development.

Apart from programming, I worked in the past as a manual web tester and a service technician in an internet provider company